{
    "id": "bc9cd24307164e0bac3a64045d4c4043",
    "title": "Sentence Completion Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "There is little water in the pond, …………………….?",
            "description": "A non-negative tag is used after negative expressions like little.",
            "answers": [
                "isn't there",
                "is there",
                "does there"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the expression at sixes and sevens mean?",
            "description": "To be at sixes and sevens is to be in a state of confusion. ",
            "answers": [
                "In a state of confusion",
                "In a state of conflict",
                "In a state of frustration"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The bell …………………….. for over two minutes.",
            "description": "To talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present, use the present perfect continuous tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "has been ringing",
                "have been ringing",
                "had been ringing"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………. have you been waiting here?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "How soon",
                "How far",
                "How long",
                "How much"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Her children have all …………………….. and left home.",
            "description": "The past participle form of grow is grown. The third form of the verb is used after has/have/had.",
            "answers": [
                "grew up",
                "grown up",
                "growned up"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "No one came, …………………….?",
            "description": "After no one, someone, anyone, we use they in tags.",
            "answers": [
                "did no one",
                "didn't they",
                "did they"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He said, ‘I have an important meeting tomorrow.’ Change into indirect speech.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "He said that he has an important meeting the next day.",
                "He said that he had an important meeting the next day.",
                "He said that he has an important meeting tomorrow."
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If the road hadn’t been slippery, they ………………………. an accident.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "wouldn’t have had",
                "wouldn't have",
                "won't have"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Sam, along with his friends, ………………….. on a holiday.",
            "description": "Here the subject is the singular noun Sam.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Give the opposite of reckless",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "heedless",
                "cautious",
                "careless",
                "ruthless"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the expression faux pas mean?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Sacrilege",
                "A grave mistake",
                "A social blunder",
                "A political blunder"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "You must be back ……………………. 8 o’clock.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "under",
                "within",
                "by",
                "in"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}